Dominick Ng

github.com/dominickng
dominickng.com

Profile

Staff Software Engineer and Engineering Manager at Google Sydney, working on Chrome OS. PhD in computer science (natural language processing and artificial intelligence) at the University of Sydney. Awarded a Fulbright Scholarship at UC Berkeley (2012 – 2013). Interested in helping people get their work done using technology, applications of big data, machine learning and data mining over large corpora and texts. Proficient with C, C++, Java, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, and related frameworks in large codebases and collaborative development environments. Extensive teaching, communication, leadership, and outreach experience.

Experience

Google
Staff Software Engineer

Sydney, AUS May 2015 – Present

Tech Lead/Manager, Chrome OS Apps Foundation team

- Facilitating a better, safer, and more featureful computing platform for users and developers
- Working on a huge open-source codebase in C++ and Java

University of Sydney – Student Recruitment Unit Senior Analyst

Sydney, AUS

May 2008 – April 2015

Delivering strategic advice and insights based on data analytics

- Analysis and processing of complex applicant and university datasets using Python and Excel
- Providing input on recruitment and operational strategies backed by data
- Developed a full-stack webapp with Django/Python/Postgres for shift management, stock monitoring, and wage calculations for over 100 staff

University of Sydney

Sydney, AUS

- Tutor (Semester Casual) (Data Structures, Informatics, Machine Principles)Jul 2009 Jun 2012
 - Tutored students in Python, Java, C, and CUDA languages in university units of study
 - Taught foundations of information processing, UNIX skills, LATEX, data structures, parallel programming and complexity, HTML/CSS, databases, and algorithms

National Computer Science School

Sydney, AUS

Tutor, Group Leader (Summer camp)

Jan 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, 2015

A camp for high school students encouraging the study of computer science

Led tutors in supervising and teaching high school students Python programming, HTML, CSS,
 Javascript, and databases to develop a social network site

ADR Design - Website Design and Development

Sydney, AUS

Partner (ongoing)

Oct 2006 – Present

Lead developer for a small web design company

Dominick Ng 2

- Designed websites and provided site hosting and maintenance for small businesses
- Managed client relations and communications

Education

University of Sydney
 Doctor of Philosophy (Natural Language Parsing)
 B.I.T. (Honours Class I and University Medal) (WAM: 91.4)
 Fulbright Scholar (Berkeley NLP Group)
 Sydney, AUS Mar 2007 - Nov 2010
 Berkeley, USA Aug 2012 - May 2013

Prizes and Scholarships

SIT Prize for Best Research Project Work, University of Sydney	2014
Fulbright Australia Postgraduate Scholarship	2012
Google Australia PhD Fellowship	2012
Australian Postgraduate Award	2011-2015
Vice Chancellor's Research Scholarship	2011-2015
University of Sydney Merit Scholarship	2007 - 2010
Capital Markets CRC High Achiever's Scholarship	2009 - 2010
University of Sydney Academic Merit Prize	2010
Allan Bromley Prize	2010
Google Prize for Excellence in Computer Science	2010
Microsoft Research Asia Prize for Senior Software Development Projects	2010
G.S. Caird Scholarship in Computer Science	2009
CISCO Prize for Networks and Distributed Systems	2008

Publications

- **Dominick Ng** and James R. Curran (2015). Identifying Cascading Errors using Constraints in Dependency Parsing. In *ACL*, pages 1148 1158. [http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P/P15/P15-1111.pdf]
- Sunghwan Mac Kim, **Dominick Ng**, Mark Johnson and James R. Curran (2012). Improving Combinatory Categorial Grammar Parse Reranking with Dependency Grammar Features. In *COLING*, pages 1441 1458. [http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P/P12/P12-1052.pdf]
- **Dominick Ng** and James R. Curran (2012). Dependency Hashing for *n*-best CCG Parsing. In *ACL*, pages 497 505. [http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/U/U10/U10-1014.pdf]
- **Dominick Ng**, Matthew Honnibal, and James R. Curran (2010). Reranking a wide coverage CCG parser. In *ALTW*, pages 90 98. [http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/U/U10/U10-1014.pdf]

References

Available upon request.